alright should we close the door yes
好吧，我们应该关上门吗
thank you so sir it's a little bit of
谢谢你，先生，这有点
background noise okay thank you
背景噪音好吗谢谢
so welcome everybody my name is Mike
所以欢迎大家，我叫麦克
Mike Fitch and this my colleague Wayne
迈克·菲奇（Mike Fitch）和我的同事韦恩（Wayne）
Beaton I think we know almost everybody
比顿我想我们几乎都认识
in the room hi for the people I don't
在房间里为我不喜欢的人打招呼
know well so we're here to talk today
很了解，所以我们今天在这里聊天
about the Eclipse Foundation
关于Eclipse基金会
specification process and I guess it
规范过程，我猜是
helps if you turn this on and so this is
帮助，如果您打开它，所以这是
the rough agenda the backgrounds
粗略的议程背景
creating the the process itself what do
创建流程本身做什么
we mean by a spec the actual process and
我们用规格表示实际过程，
then since many people here are familiar
那么既然这里的很多人都很熟悉
or many people that are that are
或很多人
interested in this process are familiar
对这个过程感兴趣的人很熟悉
the JCP so a couple of slides on what's
JCP，那么关于什么的几张幻灯片
different between the elucidation spec
阐明规范之间的差异
process and the JCP and then finally
流程和JCP，最后
closed off with some thoughts some some
有些想法关闭了一些
points on certification and branding so
关于认证和品牌的要点
background so why the heck is the
背景，为什么会这样
Eclipse Foundation doing specs in the
Eclipse Foundation在
first place and it's sort of a
第一名，有点像
opportunity meets necessity sort of
机会遇上必要
thing where we've been actually thinking
我们一直在思考的事情
about this for a while because we're big
关于这一段时间，因为我们很大
believers that open standards and open
开放标准和开放的信徒
specifications and open source are very
规格和开源都非常
complementary to one another and and but
相互补充，但
but we actually were hit basically
但实际上我们基本上受到打击
handed an opportunity that forced our
带来了一个迫使我们
hand
手
when roughly a year ago it was announced
大约一年前宣布
that that oracle was going to be moving
那个甲骨文将要移动
Java EE to the Eclipse Foundation and as
Java EE和Eclipse Foundation
part of that you we needed a spec
其中的一部分，我们需要一个规格
process to replace the JCP but we
更换JCP的过程，但我们
already know that there are other
已经知道还有其他
projects with the new clips community
新剪辑社区的项目
that are interested in doing this so we
对此有兴趣的人，所以我们
expect that this is going to be
期望这将是
something that is going to be used
将要使用的东西
elsewhere so this is the Eclipse
其他地方，这就是Eclipse
Foundation spec process this is not the
基础规范过程不是
Jakarta EE spec process although pretty
Jakarta EE规范流程虽然很漂亮
much everything we say here is going to
我们在这里所说的一切都会
be true of jakarta ii it is for use
雅加达二世是真的
across the Eclipse Foundation and we do
整个Eclipse基金会，我们
expect that
期望
and we already know of other projects
我们已经知道其他项目
that they want to do this oops so what's
他们想要这样做哎呀，那是什么
the big deal what are yr specs useful
重要的是您的规格有用吗
and and certainly you can meet folks in
而且当然可以在
an open source that'll say all you need
一个可以满足您所有需求的开源软件
is open source you don't ever need to
是您永远不需要的开源
have a spec process but specs do help in
有规范流程，但规范确实有助于
terms of collectively defining an idea
集体定义一个概念的术语
and I think it's very important to note
我认为这很重要
that just because your open source code
那仅仅是因为你的开源代码
happens to be really cool and perfect in
碰巧真的很酷很完美
all ways because you wrote it other
所有的方式，因为你写了其他
people might have different ways or
人们可能有不同的方式或
different opinions on how to implement
关于如何实施的不同意见
something and specs in the whole spec
整个规格中的某些内容和规格
process specifically designed to enable
专为实现而设计的过程
multiple implementations and where you
多种实现方式以及您在哪里
have soon as you have multiple
有多个
implementations then allowing for
然后实现
interoperability becomes a thing right
互操作性成为正确的事情
because as soon as you have multiple
因为一旦你有多个
implementations even then
甚至实现
interoperability between those
这些之间的互操作性
implementations is done is done through
实现是通过以下方式完成的
spec processes so some guiding
规范流程，因此需要一些指导
principles some guiding principles in
原则中的一些指导原则
terms of what we thought of when we were
我们当时的想法
putting together the Eclipse Foundation
组合Eclipse基金会
spec process first one is code first and
规范流程的第一个是代码优先，
what do we mean by code first so one of
我们首先说代码是什么意思
my pet peeves with the JCP since forever
我的宠物永远陪着JCP
was and you saw this more in the early
过去，您在早期就看到了更多
days of the JCB but this this notion
JCB的日子，但是这个概念
that in this I'm exaggerating to make a
在此我夸大了
point but the the very idea that the way
点，但这个方法的想法
to innovate is get a bunch of people in
创新就是吸引一群人
a room and write a spec I think is
一个房间，写一个我认为是
inherently stupid like not that I have
天生就是愚蠢的，就像我没有
an opinion I just think that that's not
我只是认为那不是
how progress is made in in software
软件方面如何取得进展
technology the way that you make
科技，您的制作方式
progress is that you experiment you
进步是你在尝试
innovate first through writing things
通过写东西先创新
out and I think I made this point
出来，我想我已经指出了这一点
previously is is like before I think
以前就像我想之前
something should be specified there are
应该指定一些东西
two things that have to be done first
首先必须做的两件事
the first is you have to actually build
首先是您必须实际构建
something that demonstrates that it can
证明它可以
be built right
建立正确
you know there's all kinds of things
你知道有各种各样的事情
that you could write a specification for
你可以写一个规范
on a piece of paper that would either
在一张纸上
maybe not impossible but extremely
也许不是不可能，但非常
difficult to build so the first thing is
很难建造，所以第一件事是
actually prove that you can solve a
实际证明您可以解决
problem and the second thing you need
问题和您需要的第二件事
before it's worth specifying is actually
在值得指定之前
demonstrate that anybody cares right
证明任何人都在乎权利
lots of people can wrote me a write
很多人可以写信给我
software that nobody cares about but if
没有人关心的软件，但是如果
you if you neither written software nor
如果您既没有编写软件也没有编写
demonstrated that anybody cares why go
证明有人在乎为什么
to all the problem all the trouble of
解决所有问题
writing a spec so when we say when we
写规范，所以当我们说何时
say code first what we're saying is we
首先说代码我们在说的是我们
want to lead through innovation through
希望通过创新来领导
through building open-source
通过构建开源
implementations demonstrating that
实施证明
somebody actually wants to use this
有人真的想用这个
stuff and at that point then okay let's
东西，那好吧，让我们
talk about turning into a spec next
接下来谈谈成为规格
guiding principle is and this is sort of
指导原则是，这有点
a delta to the JCP is no spec lead so no
JCP的增量没有规范优势，所以没有
central control point for all of the IP
所有IP的中央控制点
that's involved in the specification and
规范中涉及的内容
and basically we want to create a
基本上我们想创建一个
vendor-neutral collaborative process
与供应商无关的协作过程
with no one company in charge and that's
没有一家公司负责，那就是
so and that's really what you know if
所以这就是你所知道的
you read the JCP process it never says
您阅读了从未说过的JCP流程
well there's only a couple of places
好吧，只有几个地方
where it actually mentions oracle but it
它实际上提到甲骨文，但它
says spec lead a lot it just happens
说规格领先很多，只是发生了
that 99 times out of 100 Oracle happens
100次Oracle中有99次发生
to be the spec team but so we were
成为规格团队，但是我们
trying to come up with a vendor neutral
试图提出一个中立的供应商
approach we want to run specs as open
我们希望以开放方式运行规格的方法
source projects in a much more
源项目更多
collaborative way compatible
协作方式兼容
implementations rather than one
实现而不是一个
reference implementation so in the JCP
参考实施，因此在JCP中
and in a lot of other places you have
在很多其他地方
like a reference implementation so we're
像参考实施，所以我们
gonna go we're going with a notion that
我们要走的是
you need you can have more than one and
您需要可以有多个
in particular that means that you don't
特别是这意味着您不会
have a normative implementation self
具有规范的实施自我
certification and branding and we'll
认证和品牌，我们将
talk about those I'm gonna hand the
谈论那些我要交的
baton to Wayne for a little bit okay all
指挥棒到韦恩一点都可以
right so for the Jakarta EE
对Jakarta EE来说是正确的
specification process itself our key
规范过程本身就是我们的关键
deliverables for this year
今年的可交付成果
actually developed this specification
实际开发了此规范
process and the compatibility process
过程和兼容性过程
and brand licensing so we actually do
和品牌许可，所以我们实际上
have a brand associated with the Jakarta
拥有与雅加达相关的品牌
EEE specification sorry the Jakarta EEE
EEE规范对不起，雅加达EEE
well yeah so implementations of the
是的，所以
jacquard EEE specification will be able
提花EEE规格将能够
to use these this brand but anyway so
使用这些品牌，但无论如何
we're we're well on track to do this we
我们很乐意做到这一点，我们
decided we wanted to start with the
决定我们要从
Eclipse development process clips
Eclipse开发过程剪辑
development process exists it's been
开发过程已经存在
used to successfully develop open source
用于成功开发开源
projects for for many years we figured
我们想了很多年的项目
we kind of knew what we were doing in
我们有点知道我们在做什么
that area and using that as a basis
该区域并以此为基础
seemed to make a lot of sense it
似乎很有道理
provides a lot of the governance and the
提供了很多治理和
structures that that are actually
实际上是
required to do this work and it you know
需要做这项工作，你知道吗
it does also have the ability or leave
它也有能力或离开
leave much of the actual process to the
将大部分实际过程留给
individual project team so day to day
各个项目团队如此日常
operations is really something that is
操作确实是
specific to a particular project team
特定于特定项目团队
whether they what form of agile process
他们是否以哪种形式的敏捷过程
they follow or what not the Eclipse
他们遵循或不是Eclipse
development process is based around the
开发过程围绕
notions of transparency openness
透明公开的概念
meritocracy and vendor neutrality
精英和供应商中立
actually vendor neutrality I would
我实际上是卖方中立的
should put a star beside it that's
应该在它旁边放一个星星
actually not listed as an open source
实际上没有列为开源
rule of engagement in this version of
此版本的参与规则
the current version of the Eclipse
当前版本的Eclipse
development process but it probably will
开发过程，但可能会
much of what we do is focused around
我们所做的大部分工作都围绕着
making sure that a playing field is
确保有一个公平的竞争环境
level so that everybody gets to come and
水平，以便每个人都可以来
play by the same set of rules everybody
每个人都遵循相同的规则
has the same ability to participate the
具有相同的参与能力
Eclipse development process if you were
Eclipse开发过程
to formalize it would look a little bit
正式化看起来会有点
like this and I'm just gonna splash this
像这样，我只是要飞溅这个
up quickly because I'm gonna compare it
快起来，因为我要比较
with some changes compare what we're
进行一些更改比较我们
doing with the spec process later there
稍后在那里进行规范流程
is definitely we start with proposal
绝对是我们从提案开始
creation review winds up basically
创作评论基本结束
creating a project project goes into a
创建项目项目进入
development mode they produce milestones
他们创造里程碑的发展模式
those milestone builds over over a
这些里程碑跨越了一个
release cycle eventually result in a
发行周期最终导致
release candidate that's sent forward
释放已发送的候选
for a release review and project
用于发布审查和项目
releases then they go into planning for
发布，然后他们开始计划
their next release planning tends to be
他们的下一个发布计划往往是
informal for a lot of our projects but
在我们的很多项目中都非正式
at various levels of formality the
在各种形式的
eclipse top-level project for example
例如，eclipse顶级项目
does a great deal
做了很多
of advanced planning there anyway that's
无论如何，高级计划
just just a you know kind of snapshot
只是一个您知道的快照
that in your mind cuz I'm going to show
在你的脑海里，我要展示
a similar diagram in in a little while
不久后会有类似的图
the with the architecture council is
与建筑委员会的是
going to be presenting the board of
将要介绍的董事会
directors with an update to the Eclipse
导演，并更新了Eclipse
development process we'll be doing that
开发过程中我们将这样做
over the next couple of days well the
在接下来的几天里
meeting in November 14th is when the the
11月14日的会议是
board of directors will have a chance to
董事会将有机会
approve this for us we've introduced the
为我们批准了这一点，我们介绍了
notion of a progress review which will
进度审查的概念
be valuable for the specification
对规范有价值
process the progress review also will be
处理进度审查也将是
not a replacement so much but an
不是那么多的替代品，而是
alternative for projects to do releases
项目发布的替代方法
so just regular Eclipse open source
所以只是常规的Eclipse开源
projects can engage in a progress review
项目可以参与进度审查
and then for one year after they can do
然后他们可以做一年
releases as they need to without further
根据需要释放
ceremony they would still be required to
仪式，他们仍然需要
follow the IP policy which means all
遵循IP政策，这意味着
intellectual property would have to be
知识产权必须是
cleared by the intellectual property
由知识产权清除
team before that we also took the step
团队之前，我们也迈出了一步
of formalizing a list of terms which
形式化的术语列表
seems like it's a long time coming
似乎很长一段时间了
curiously we we really took a long time
奇怪的是我们真的花了很长时间
coming up with definitions of project
提出项目的定义
and release turns out those are actually
释放出来实际上是
relatively hard things to define we came
定义我们来的相对困难的事情
up with some fairly concise definitions
用一些相当简洁的定义
though which I'm happy with so the
虽然我很满意所以
Eclipse Foundation specification project
Eclipse Foundation规范项目
extends this we try to take an approach
扩展这一点，我们尝试采取一种方法
of just enough process we didn't want to
只是足够的过程，我们不想
keep it we want to keep it lightweight
保持它，我们要保持它轻便
we want to make it so that innovation
我们希望做到这一点，以便创新
the specification process itself didn't
规范过程本身并没有
get in the way of innovation the we are
阻碍创新，我们就是
introducing the notion of a
介绍一个概念
specification project which is just a
规范项目，这只是一个
designation we have we have we have open
指定我们拥有我们拥有我们开放
source projects right now this is just a
源项目现在这只是一个
special flag on a project this also and
项目上的特殊标志
I'll talk more about this later aligns
稍后我会详细讨论
projects with working groups formally
与工作组正式合作的项目
which is something we we don't do with
我们不这样做
regular projects and there's different
常规项目，有不同的
approvals and we'll talk a bit more
批准，我们再谈一点
about that and then we introduced the
关于这一点，然后我们介绍了
notion of participants and participant
参与者和参与者的概念
representatives which again I'll talk to
代表，我将再次与之交谈
in a few minutes did you want to do this
在几分钟之内你想这样做吗
you can tell we've carefully rehearsed
你可以告诉我们我们已经认真排练了
this oh this is a picture on I just
哦，这是我的照片
kidding so what do we mean by a
开玩笑的意思是
specification so specification is a
规格，所以规格是
collection of api's descriptions of
api的描述集合
semantic behavior data formats and/or
语义行为数据格式和/或
protocols intended to enable the
旨在使
development of independent compatible
开发独立兼容
implementations actually the word
实现实际上是这个词
independent there is particularly
独立特别有
important it's very possible to write a
重要的是，写一个
specification that's based on a
基于
particular implementation and tied to
特定的实现并与之相关
that particular implementation but the
该特定的实现，但
whole point of the spec process that
整个规范流程
we're creating is the enablement of
我们正在创造的是
independent implementations even if
独立的实现，即使
there are never is one right it's
从来没有一种权利是
possible that you could do an open
可能你可以做一个公开的
source project that just everybody loves
每个人都喜欢的源项目
and it's perfect in every way and you
在任何方面都完美无缺
still do a spec for it because it's
仍然为此做一个规格，因为
useful and if you know somebody maybe
有用的，如果你认识某人，也许
nobody ever is motivated to create an
没有人有动力去创造一个
independent implementation but that
独立执行，但是
there's a certain quality statement
有一定的质量声明
inherent in saying that you want to
内在地说你想
enable independent implementations right
启用独立的实施权
if you do that then the spec is is is
如果您这样做，那么规格是
going to be of better quality than
质量会比
something that's tied to a particular
与特定事物相关的事物
one so the artifacts that we want every
所以我们想要的每件艺术品
specification to include is there has to
要包括的规范
be specification document there has to
需要的规格文件
be some technical artifact that's
是一些技术工件
actually kind of optional but for
实际上是可选的，但对于
example in the context of the java
Java上下文中的示例
language there should be a jar file that
语言应该有一个jar文件
gives you the interfaces that you're
为您提供您所需要的界面
defining in the specification and you
在规范中定义，您
can pick up that you can pick up that
可以拿起，你可以拿到
spec document pick up the API jar file
规范文档提取API jar文件
and go off and do an independent
去做一个独立的
implementation then there also needs to
实施，然后还需要
be a TCK and one thing that's sort of a
成为TCK，一件事有点像
subtle but important point is your
微妙但重要的一点是
implementation is not a compatible is
实现不兼容是
not compatible to the TCK
与TCK不兼容
your implementation is compatible to the
您的实现与
specification the TCK is the mechanism
规范TCK是机制
by which you demonstrate that
以此证明
compatibility subtle but important point
兼容性微妙但重要的一点
and finally like we said there's no
最后就像我们说的，没有
single reference implementation but
单一参考实现，但
before you can say that the spec is
在您可以说规格是
final there has to be
最后必须有
at least one compatible implementation
至少一种兼容的实现
available in open-source so again there
可以在开源中使用
has to be at least one there could be
必须至少有一个
five but before you can say the spec is
五，但在您可以说规格之前
done you have to be able to prove to the
你必须能够证明
spec committee that somebody is capable
有能力的规格委员会
of implementing this in passing the TCK
通过TCK来实现这一点
before the spec goes final so the spec
在规格最终确定之前，所以规格
document I probably just said everything
文件我可能只是说了一切
for the non next five slides so the spec
对于非下五个幻灯片，因此规格
document is obviously text there may be
文件显然是文字，可能有
optional parts and but it must be
可选零件，但必须是
possible to implement all optional parts
可以实现所有可选部件
and there's a actually in that I don't
实际上，我没有
know if you have a slide for this but
知道你是否有一张幻灯片，但是
there is a rule that if when we say
有一个规则，如果我们说
there has to be at least one compatible
必须至少有一个兼容
implementation that compatible
兼容的实现
implementation has to implement all all
实现必须实现所有
of the optional parts right so you can't
正确的可选零件，所以您不能
go final when there's no demonstration
没有示范时进入决赛
that the whole spec is done and if you
整个规格已经完成，如果您
if you include other specs by reference
如果您通过引用包括其他规格
you can't / you can't override those
你不能/你不能覆盖那些
rules that are if they if it's been
如果他们曾经是的规则
specified as non optional in the spec
在规范中指定为非可选
that you're that you're referencing then
那就是你所引用的
you can't override that in your spec so
您不能在规范中覆盖它，因此
this teach each spec has to have a TCK
这教每个规范必须有一个TCK
and the TCK can be different for each
每个人的TCK可以不同
versions and the TCK has to be under one
版本和TCK必须在1以下
of the approved open-source licenses and
批准的开源许可证的数量和
we'll talk about what those open-source
我们将讨论那些开源
licenses are in a sec but again the TCK
许可证是在几秒钟内，但再次是TCK
is there to demonstrate that an
在那里证明
implementation can be an it is
实现可以是
compatible and actually a brief comment
兼容，实际上是一个简短的评论
on tcks one of the things that we think
在我们看来，其中一件事情
is going to be a fundamental difference
将是一个根本的区别
between in the context of Jakarta in the
在雅加达的背景下
future relative to the status code today
相对于今天状态码的未来
is the simple fact that the tcks
简单的事实是
are going our open source is a huge
我们的开源是巨大的
differentiator right like right now if
如果现在，微分器现在就正确
you if you're a Java EE 8 license or
如果您具有Java EE 8许可证，或者
it's incredibly the TCK is incredibly
令人难以置信的是TCK令人难以置信
confidential it's so confidential that
机密是如此机密
it's actually breaking the contract if
实际上是在违约
you publish your results publicly right
您可以公开发布结果
so the interaction between you and
所以你和
basically the interaction between you
基本上你们之间的互动
and the spec
和规格
determines on whether or not you can
确定您是否可以
claim compatibility and all of that is
声称兼容性，而所有这些都是
done privately we're expecting that
私下里完成，我们期望
because the T CK's are open source the
因为T CK是开源的
publication of results are going to be
结果的发布将是
publicly available that a lot of the
公开提供了很多
behaviors that happen in the ecosystem
生态系统中发生的行为
are going to be open and transparent and
将是开放和透明的，
that's going to help everybody innovate
这将帮助每个人创新
it's going to be a huge difference that
这将是巨大的差异
if you see if there's a test in the t ck
如果你看是否有测试
that's bogus right the conversation
在对话中是假的
about how bogus that is is now going to
关于现在有多假
be public not some private conversation
公开而不是私人对话
between you and Oracle and that is it
在您和Oracle之间，仅此而已
that's a really really big difference so
那真的是很大的不同，所以
compatible implementations so yep you
兼容的实现，是的
have to be able to demonstrate that
必须能够证明
there's at least one again has to be
至少必须有一个
them into an open-source license and we
他们变成了开源许可证，我们
think that's important so before the
认为这很重要，所以在
spec is done there has to be an open
规范已经完成，必须有一个开放
source implementation there can be other
源实现中可以有其他
ones that proprietary implementations
具有专有实现的
are you know perfectly fine but you
你知道很好吗，但是你
can't you can't claim the spec as final
难道你不能声称规格是最终的
based on one of those and as I said
基于其中之一，正如我所说
earlier at least one compatible
较早的至少一个兼容
implementation has to implement all the
实施必须实施所有
optional parts so what do we mean by an
可选零件，所以我们所说的是什么
open source license so there's three EPL
开源许可证，所以有三个EPL
2.0 and only 2.0 the BSD 3 clause and
BSD 3子句仅2.0和仅2.0
Apache those are the three choices in
这些是Apache的三个选择
the Eclipse Foundation spec process it
Eclipse Foundation规范对其进行处理
says that other licenses can be added at
说可以在以下位置添加其他许可证
the request of the of the work of that
该工作的要求
working group and that that would also
工作组，那也
have to be approved by the Board of
必须获得董事会的批准
Directors because the way things work at
董事，因为事情的运作方式
Eclipse is any time we use a license
Eclipse是我们使用许可证的任何时间
other than the EPL it needs board
除了EPL，它还需要董事会
approval the board is approve has
董事会批准的批准
delegated to me the ability to also
授权给我的能力
approve bsd and apache
批准bsd和apache
as the executive director but any
作为执行董事，但任何
license other than those three would
除了这三个以外的其他许可证
have to be approved unanimously by the
必须获得
board and I can pretty much guarantee
董事会，我可以保证
you that if you were like if you're if
你，如果你喜欢，如果你
your suggestion is GPL 3.0 that's not
您的建议是GPL 3.0，不是
going to fly
会飞
yes Dan
是的，丹
is a question yeah aren't we also able
是一个问题，是不是我们也能够
to take to the board request you
登上董事会要求您
wouldn't actually dot you wouldn't need
实际上不会点你不需要
to go to the board for that if you want
如果愿意，可以去董事会
to remove one of those you could do that
删除其中一个您可以做到的
at the working group level okay
在工作组一级好
you just can't add one without the
如果没有，就无法添加一个
approval of the board so these this is
董事会的批准，这是
largely sort of being done for backwards
很大程度上是为了倒退
compatibility that JCP had this notion
JCP具有此概念的兼容性
of their specs and then there's profiles
他们的规格，然后有个人资料
which are collections of specs and then
是规格的集合，然后
there's the notion of platform which is
有平台的概念是
sort of baked right into the JCP process
直接进入JCP流程
and really from from our the way our
真的是从我们的方式
spec process is is these are all just
规范的过程就是这些
specs but a working group can decide
规格，但工作组可以决定
that some spec probably it which is a
某些规格可能是
collection of other specs we can be
我们可以成为其他规格的集合
labeled as a profile and there could be
标为个人资料，可能会有
a choice by the working group to say
工作组选择说
there's a profile that's so
有一个个人资料
extra-special we're gonna we're gonna
特别，我们要去
call it a platform but these are
称它为平台，但这些是
basically branding exercises there but
那里基本上是品牌练习，但是
the one the one thing that's actually
一件事实际上是一件事
sort of ute is special about profiles
ute对个人资料很特别
and platforms is that certainly in the
和平台肯定是在
case of Jakarta the brand that the
雅加达品牌案例
little sail ship can only be attached to
小帆船只能连接到
a profile or a platform so the brand is
个人资料或平台，因此品牌是
not attached to a single spec so you
没有附加到单个规范，所以您
don't say hey we're servlet you know 4.0
不要说嘿我们是servlet，您知道4.0
compatible and I'm putting the sailing
兼容，我在航行
ship on on servlet you have to have web
在servlet上运行，您必须具有网络
profile or a full profile or Jakarta EE
个人资料或完整个人资料或Jakarta EE
platform you have to implement all of
平台，您必须实施所有
that in order to actually put the
为了真正把
sailing ship on it so the spec process
帆船就这样规范流程
I've mentioned this before just enough
我刚刚提到过这个
process it's based on EDP the IP flows
基于EDP处理IP流
are similar to the rest of the way
与其余方式相似
eclipse works but patents are a little
蚀的作品，但专利有点
bit special because patents the way
有点特别，因为获得专利
patents work in specs is different than
规范中的专利工作与
the way patents work in open source
专利在开源中的工作方式
licenses and it's probably worth just
许可证，可能值得
taking a moment to explain that so the
花一点时间解释一下
way say the apache license work in the
方式说apache许可在
eclipse public license work is yes there
蚀公共许可证工作是有的
are royalty-free patent grants in those
是那些中的免版税专利授权
licenses but
许可证但是
those patent licenses only apply to the
这些专利许可仅适用于
contribution being made by that company
该公司正在作出的贡献
so IBM contributes code to the Eclipse
因此IBM为Eclipse贡献了代码
IDE project if there's any patents as
IDE项目，如果有任何专利
they read on that it only covers that
他们读到它只涵盖了
contribution in the context of the
在以下方面的贡献
Eclipse IDE project so I be an IBM's
Eclipse IDE项目，让我成为IBM的
patents on that cot that we Don that
我们在那张婴儿床上拥有专利
contribution plus what was in the
贡献加上
Eclipse IDE on the day they made the
他们制作的那天是Eclipse IDE
contribution right so it's a quite a
贡献的权利，所以这是一个相当
narrowly defined patent license the way
狭义定义专利许可的方式
specifications work and that's not this
规格有效，不是这样
is not just unique to ours this is
不只是我们的独特
basically when somebody says there's a
基本上，当有人说有一个
spec and this is why specs are different
规格，这就是为什么规格不同的原因
than open source implementations is the
比开源实现更重要的是
waste patent grants work in a
废物专利授权工作
specification context is if IBM is
规范上下文是IBM是否
involved in a spec and they contribute
参与规范，他们做出了贡献
to the spec the entire IBM patent
按照规格，整个IBM专利
portfolio that is would be necessarily
有必要的投资组合
infringed by any implementation of that
受到任何实施的侵害
spec regardless of who does it and
规范，不管是谁做的，以及
regardless of whether it's open source
不管它是否开源
of proprietary any implementation of
专有的任何实现
that specification gets a royalty-free
该规范免版税
patent license to all essential claims
所有基本要求的专利许可
that are owned by IBM so as you can see
如您所见，它们归IBM所有
the the patent licensing in in in a
中的专利许可
specification context is a much larger
规范上下文要大得多
and broader patent license than what you
比您更广泛的专利许可
get in open source licenses and so
获得开源许可证等等
that's that's definitely something that
那绝对是那件事
we've spent a lot of time thinking about
我们花了很多时间思考
and working on and it finally
并继续努力，最后
customizable means the each working
可定制的意味着每个工作
group that wants to do a spec process at
想要在以下位置进行规格处理的小组
eclipse based on this spec process can
基于此规范过程的日食可以
slightly modify it within certain
在一定范围内略微修改
parameters and it's mostly around making
参数，这主要是围绕
sure that they don't mess up the IP I'll
确保他们不会搞乱IP，我会
hand it back to Wayne so a specification
交还给韦恩
as we've introduced the notion of a
正如我们介绍的概念
specification project it's a special
规范项目，这是一个特殊的项目
type of project that is dead hard and me
项目类型，这对我来说是非常艰辛的
is designated as a specification project
被指定为规范项目
it's owned by a particular working group
它由一个特定的工作组拥有
so we have a
所以我们有一个
there we're specification projects are
那里是规范项目
part of a single working group they
他们是单个工作组的一部分
require for the different reviews that
需要不同的评论
they engage in right now pmc approval is
他们现在参与PMC的批准是
required for most reviews we require an
大多数评论都需要我们要求
additional approval of a specification
规范的额外批准
committee specification committee is
委员会规格委员会是
aligned with a a working group and we've
与一个工作组保持一致，我们已经
introduced a special class of committer
介绍了特殊的提交者类
which I'll talk about in a second here
我会在这里转载
so who's who so I have a rabbit pointer
所以谁是谁，我有一个兔子指针
here I'm not gonna touch I'm gonna wreck
在这里我不会碰我会破坏
something I don't be like Vinnie this
我不像温妮这样的东西
morning
早上
so we have a specification project in
所以我们有一个规范项目
the middle we have the obvious group of
中间我们有明显的
committers and contributors along the
沿线的贡献者和贡献者
bottom of this diagram the PMC it's up
该图的底部是PMC
at the top they're providing the
在顶部，他们提供了
governments and oversight we've added in
我们加入的政府和监督
the the notion of a specification
规范的概念
committee the specification committee is
规范委员会是
aligned with a particular working group
与特定工作组保持一致
that specification committee does also
该规范委员会也
provide approvals like I said on on the
提供批准，就像我在
different
不同
lifecycle events of a specification
规范的生命周期事件
project they're part of the IP integrity
项目它们是IP完整性的一部分
equation as well the the other thing the
等式还有另一件事
thing I actually just wanted to include
我实际上只想包括的东西
how companies relate here there's
公司如何联系这里
actually no direct relationship between
实际上之间没有直接关系
an organization or company and a project
组织或公司以及项目
at the Eclipse Foundation we deal or I
在Eclipse Foundation，我们交易
deal in projects and committers and
处理项目和提交者，以及
contributors and PM CS and that sort of
贡献者和PM CS等
thing and organizations exert influence
事物和组织施加影响
into this process by employing a
通过使用一个
committer they exert influence by by
他们通过施加影响
joining the working group and having
加入工作组并
participating on the the steering
参与转向
committee that's and that's again with
委员会是，那又是
the the more direct alignment between
之间的直接对齐
the working groups and the specification
工作组和规范
projects there's actually a little
项目实际上有一点
there's there's more a higher level of
还有更高的水平
control for an organization in this
在此控制组织
equation
方程
specification committers now we've we
规范提交者
with specifications we have a few
根据规格，我们有一些
differences so it's basically everything
差异，所以基本上就是一切
that a committer is on a on a regular
提交者定期上
project but the committer must be a
项目，但提交者必须是
member of the Eclipse Foundation now to
Eclipse Foundation的成员现在
do that
去做
the committer must either work for a
提交者必须为
member company or must themselves sign
会员公司或必须自己签字
our member agreement as an individual
我们的会员协议作为个人
committer there's just some some legal
提交者，有些法律
legal cover that comes with that and
随之而来的法律保障
they must also sign and/or be covered by
他们还必须签名并/或被
the working group participation
工作组的参与
agreement again they can get this by
再次达成协议，他们可以通过
virtue of working for a member company
在会员公司工作的优点
that has signed that agreement or as an
已签署该协议或作为
individual member committer committee
个人委员提交委员会
member member committee member commit or
成员成员委员会成员承诺或
they can sign that that diet that
他们可以签署该饮食
document on their own and that that's
自己记录文件，那就是
the working group participation
工作组的参与
agreement is the one that's primarily
协议是主要的
concerned with patents yes the new
与专利有关，是新的
notion of so one of the challenges that
因此，挑战之一
we have you know as mike was suggesting
我们知道迈克在暗示
there the the way the IPS flow IP flows
IPS流IP流的方式
into a specification project is a little
进入规范项目有点
bit different and one of the things we
有点不同，其中之一是我们
need to do is guarantee that an
需要做的是保证
organization can stay involved in a
组织可以继续参与
project so if a committer representing
因此，如果一个提交者代表
an organization retires we need a way of
一个组织退休，我们需要一种方法
immediately replacing them so we've
立即更换它们，以便我们
introduced the notion of a participant
介绍了参与者的概念
representative I guess I should back up
代表我想我应该备份
and talk about participants a
并谈论参与者
participant is an organization that
参与者是一个组织
participates in a specification so an
参与规范，因此
organization will assert that they care
组织会断言他们在乎
about a particular specification and by
关于特定规范
so doing they have the ability to
因此，他们有能力
basically appoint a representative onto
基本上任命一名代表
onto the project and that representative
到项目和那个代表
is a commit becomes a committer and they
是一个提交成为提交者，他们
have all the requirements that I had
有我的所有要求
mentioned earlier I just wanted to add
前面提到我只是想添加
that and the reason why this is
那就是为什么
necessary is because it's through the
必要的是因为它是通过
this participation that ultimately binds
这种参与最终约束
that company's patent portfolio to the
该公司的专利组合
patent license grants that I was talking
我正在谈论的专利许可授予
about earlier right so it would be
关于较早的权利，所以它将是
unfair to say that you know red hat
不公平地说你知道戴红色帽子
patent portfolio was going to apply to
专利组合将适用于
this spec if they were uninvolved in the
此规范，如果他们不参与
spec and by putting a committer and part
规范，并放置一个提交者和一部分
tip in by participating in the spec
通过参与规范来提示
that's the mechanism that binds their
这是绑定他们的机制
patent portfolio to the spec so you
专利组合，使您
recall the I'm sure you recall in in
记得我记得你在
vivid detail the earlier version of this
生动的细节
document what is changed again I put
记录下我再次更改的内容
that document up earlier because I
那个文件提早了，因为我
wanted that picture up earlier because I
想要早点那张照片，因为我
wanted to just sort of highlight that
只是想强调一下
this looks really scary and everybody I
这看起来真的很吓人，我每个人
show this to kind of goes on their eyes
向他们展示这种感觉
get really big but fundamentally it's
变得很大，但从根本上讲
not that different from what we do today
与我们今天所做的没有什么不同
I've introduced sorry we have introduced
我介绍了抱歉，我们介绍了
a plan review so proposal is created
计划审核，以便创建提案
project does a creation review that
专案进行创作审查，
creation review that proposal serves as
提案充当的创作审核
the plan for the first iteration so we
第一次迭代的计划，所以我们
drop right into development after that
之后立即投入发展
just like the regular process project
就像常规流程项目一样
will issue milestone build and continue
将发布里程碑并继续
development throughout some number of my
我的一些发展
loose um number of milestones which the
数量稀疏的里程碑
project can decide or maybe the
项目可以决定或者
specification committee and working
规格委员会和工作
group can make some recommendations in
小组可以在
terms of how many milestones they
他们有多少里程碑的条件
produce some number of those milestones
产生一些里程碑
need to be taken through a progress
需要取得进展
review that progress review requires
进度审查要求的审查
approval by supermajority of the
绝大多数的批准
specification committee that iteration
规格委员会那次迭代
again we way we've envisioned it at
再次，我们已经设想到了
least one progress review must be
必须至少进行一次进度审查
undertaken during development right and
在开发权期间进行
for those who are familiar with the JCP
对于那些熟悉JCP的人
process so you could choose to have a
过程，因此您可以选择
progress review and basically tell
进度审查，基本上可以告诉
everybody that this is your early draft
大家这是你的初稿
review and if you mean so basically this
评论，如果您的意思是这样
is sort of an abstraction but if you
是某种抽象，但是如果您
wanted to model the exact JCP process
想要为确切的JCP流程建模
using this you could so at some point we
使用这个你可以在某个时候
decide that we're done we take a
决定我们完成了，我们采取
specification version this we I'd call
我将其称为规范版本
this a this was a release candidate in
这是这是在发布候选
the earlier document to the to the
较早的文档到
release review process release that
发布审查流程发布
again the specification committee gets a
规格委员会再次获得
vote in a
投票
to the PMC that then results in the
到PMC，然后导致
specification version becoming what we
规范版本成为我们的
call a final specification or a ratified
称为最终规格或已批准
specification and then the cycle repeats
规格，然后重复循环
that that final line that loops back
最后那条循环回去
that maybe there may be months years
可能有几个月的时间
days you know a latency there but the
天，你知道那里有延迟，但是
the project would engage in planning for
该项目将参与规划
their next release that plan then needs
然后计划需要的下一个版本
to be approved by the specification
由规范批准
committee before it can be taken forward
委员会才可以提出来
so the the spec committee needs to know
因此规格委员会需要知道
at the beginning of a release cycle what
在发布周期开始时，
the plans are and must approve of those
该计划是并且必须批准这些计划
plans so there's a number of things a
计划，所以有很多事情
specification committee must approve I'm
规格委员会必须批准我
gonna actually power through because
实际上会通过，因为
there's some things we need to get to in
我们需要做一些事情
six minutes
六分钟
the we have some new new versions of
我们有一些新的新版本
some some agreements I think I'm going
我想我要去的一些协议
to pass that you guys sure so a minute
让你们肯定过一会儿
yeah so yeah basically there's a couple
是的，所以基本上有几个
of things we have to do for the IP flows
IP流量我们要做的事情
to enable code first development and
启用代码优先开发和
basically what we're gonna say for both
基本上我们要为两者说
copyrights and patents is is that if you
版权和专利是，如果您
give us stuff you can't sue us later so
给我们你以后不能起诉我们的东西
and so that is going to require a change
所以这将需要改变
to the eclipse committer agreement and
蚀提交者协议和
the contribution agreement and the
贡献协议和
Terms of Use but it's all it's all I
使用条款，但仅此而已
mean of course it's written by lawyers
当然是由律师写的
so it sucks but all it says is if you
所以很烂，但它的意思是，如果你
give us stuff you know we can put it in
给我们你知道的东西，我们可以放进去
specs and you won't see us later or and
规格，以后您将不会再看到我们，或者
you won't what yeah and you won't sue
你不会的，你不会起诉
our implementers later so it's basically
稍后我们的实施者，基本上
just making it crystal clear that if you
只是清楚地说，如果你
give us stuff it's gonna go into specs
给我们一些东西，它将进入规格
and don't complain later
以后不要抱怨
so the JCP comparison so it's a little
因此，JCP比较
bit harsh to the ACP to say their
对ACP有点苛刻地说他们
specification first I would because they
首先我要说明，因为他们
have been doing a more code first stuff
一直在做更多的代码
especially lately and the Java SE side
特别是最近和Java SE方面
with basing their stuff on open JDK but
将他们的东西基于开放的JDK，但是
certainly their roots of the JCP go back
当然，他们的JCP根源可以追溯到
to a sort of a specific aspect first
首先到一个特定方面
kind of attitude what they the Executive
他们的行政态度如何
Committee of the JCP is Court of does a
JCP委员会是法院的
mixture of what we have in both the
我们在两者中都有的混合体
steering committee in the spec committee
规范委员会的指导委员会
the way we're doing it in particularly
特别是我们的做法
in Jakarta is a lot cleaner so what used
在雅加达要干净得多，所以用了什么
to be called an expert group is now
现在被称为专家组
going to be called a specification
将被称为规范
project experts are now specification
项目专家现在已成为规范
committers IP flows through the
提交者IP流经
participants versus the way it works at
参与者与它的工作方式
the JC P where it goes through the spec
符合规范的JC P
lead and both the JCP has actually got
领导和两个JCP实际上已经
pretty high marks in terms of
很高的分数
transparency and public communication
透明度和公众沟通
and so I think we're pretty equivalent
所以我认为我们相当
on that although of course at eclipse
在那当然，尽管日食
you know everything has to be public and
你知道一切都必须公开
then we also have this feature where
然后我们还有这个功能
working groups can slightly modify these
工作组可以稍作修改
things on their own so the document is
东西自己，所以文件是
open-source in our context where the
在我们的上下文中开源
document can be close source it often is
该文档通常可以是接近源的
open source and the JCP if it doesn't
开源和JCP（如果没有）
have to be the JCP actually gives the
必须是JCP实际上给了
spec lead the flexibility of choosing
规格引领选择的灵活性
their spec license to a certain degree
他们的规格许可证在一定程度上
the biggest differences I talked about
我谈到的最大差异
before is that the TCK is not only is a
以前，TCK不仅是
closed source but it's proprietary and
封闭源，但它是专有的
confidential so that that definitely is
机密，所以绝对是
a big change and then in the JCP there's
很大的变化，然后在JCP中
one normative reference implementation
一种规范的参考实现
where as we're allowing for multiple
因为我们允许多个
compatible implementations they we both
我们都兼容的实现
have the ability to create things called
有能力创造被称为
profiles and platforms so that's that's
配置文件和平台，那就是
backwards compatibility so in terms of
向后兼容，因此
claiming compatibility I'm going through
声称我正在经历的兼容性
this real quick is this very special
真正的快速是非常特别的
thing happen
事情发生
up until the point where the spec goes
直到规格达到目的为止
final it's just open source right but at
最后，它只是开源的权利，但在
the moment where the spec goes final
规格最终确定的那一刻
it's ratified by the spec committee then
然后由规格委员会批准
special things happen so the the spec
发生特殊情况，因此规格
document is pull turn into perhaps turn
文件拉转也许
into a PDF in that spec document is then
然后放入该规范文档中的PDF
licensed under the specification license
根据规范许可获得许可
the TCK is there's a there's a
TCK是那里有一个
particular binary version of it that's
它的特定二进制版本
going to be put under the TCK license
将被置于TCK许可之下
which then will allow you a name if you
然后，如果您愿意，它将允许您命名
pass it you can claim compatibility and
通过它，你可以声称兼容性和
the important thing to understand there
重要的是要在那里了解
is what we're getting to is a world
是我们要去的世界
where the tcks are completely
cks完全在哪里
open-source and you can always make
开源，您随时可以
truthful statements that iran this
伊朗的真实陈述
CK based on this and I passed all of it
CK基于此，我全部通过了
but you can't actually say I am
但你实际上不能说我是
compatible with this specification
与此规格兼容
unless you run the exact binary version
除非您运行确切的二进制版本
of the TCK under the under the TC k
TC k下的TCK
license so there's there's but there's
许可证，所以有，但是有
gonna be a much more open a lot more
将会更加开放
openness around around that world so we
那个世界的开放性，所以我们
have spec license TCK license and a
拥有规范许可证TCK许可证和
trademark license and then we'll talk a
商标许可，然后我们将讨论
second about the trademark license so
关于商标许可的第二点
this is a bit about what you're talking
这是关于你在说什么
about earlier about how these these
关于这些如何
artifacts get transmogrified from from
神器从
being open-source into being special
开源变得特别
once the spec is final and ratified of
一旦规格最终确定并获得批准
course the compatibility mutations are
当然，兼容性突变是
always under an open-source license and
始终获得开源许可，并且
then there's a self-certification that
然后有一个自我认证
happens if you that if you are fully
如果你完全的话就会发生
compatible and it fully implements the
兼容并且完全实现了
final specification fills all the
最终规格填满了所有
requirements then you can and you
要求，那么你可以和你
publicly make available your TCK test
公开提供您的TCK测试
results then you can you can claim make
结果，那么你可以声称使
truthful claims about compatibility and
关于兼容性和
then one of the biggest differences last
那么最大的差异之一就是
slides is that is around the brand right
幻灯片是围绕品牌的权利
so once you're compatible and you've
因此，一旦您兼容并且
demonstrated compatibility versus the
表现出的兼容性与
TCK then that then you can also use the
TCK，那么您也可以使用
logo to use the logo you have to sign
徽标以使用您必须签名的徽标
the trademark license agreement with the
与
Eclipse Foundation and we're not going
Eclipse Foundation，我们不会
to charge realties or license fees for
收取不动产或许可费
the trademark it's but you have to be a
它是商标，但您必须成为
member so that you have to be you know
成员，这样你就必须成为你的认识
putting a little skin into the game in
在游戏中加入一些皮肤
terms of making this all sustainable but
使这一切可持续的条件
it's not like we're gonna be licensing
这不像我们要获得许可
and getting deeply involved in in your
并深入参与您的
business solutions member yeah it's not
业务解决方案成员，是的，不是
strategic right so if you're like a
战略权利，所以如果您像
two-person startup and you want it to
两人启动，您想要
brand your implementation is Jakarta it
您实施的品牌是雅加达吗
would cost you fifteen hundred dollars a
会花你一千五百美元
year so the takeaway so we're code first
年所以外卖，所以我们首先编码
transparent community oriented in terms
透明的社区导向
of in by that we mean we're expecting
的意思是我们期望
the community to help us police a lot of
社区帮助我们警察
this and some of the behaviors that
这个和一些行为
we're anticipating are based on you know
我们期待基于您的了解
open community conversations about
公开有关的社区对话
things
东西
we think it's lighter weight it's
我们认为它的重量更轻
certainly not zero weight
肯定不是零重量
we're not this is not the github of
我们不是这不是的github
specifications there is some work that
规范中有一些工作
has to happen but we still are applying
必须发生，但我们仍在申请
the the you know the rigorous IP
您知道严格的IP
management that the Eclipse Foundation
Eclipse Foundation的管理
is is well known for and we're building
是众所周知的，我们正在建立
on the success of the the Eclipse
Eclipse的成功
development process we've demonstrated
我们已经展示了开发过程
that we've got something that works and
我们有一些可行的方法，
so we're gonna keep using that wherever
所以我们要在任何地方继续使用它
appropriate perfect you know it's gonna
合适的完美，你知道它会
be like two-phase commit kind of thing
就像两阶段提交一样的东西
right so basically they're going to be
对，所以基本上他们会是
running the open source versions and so
运行开源版本等
we all kind of settle down and then was
我们都安顿下来然后
then we're gonna do like what you're
然后我们会喜欢你的
going to weigh it will work is will
权衡一下它将起作用
deliver to the spec committee here's the
交付给规格委员会的是
spec here's the TCK and it's all version
规格这里是TCK，它是所有版本
managed right and then here's proof that
管理正确，然后这里证明
there's an implementation that passes
有一个通过的实现
this TCK so we're gonna provide evidence
这个TCK，我们将提供证据
to the spec committee that all this
给规格委员会，这一切
works they're going to ratify it and
他们将批准的工作，
poof it's now a compatible
of现在是兼容的
implementation it's like you go to you
实现就像你去找你
take communion you're trans mortified
参加圣餐，你变得反感
it's like you know they make it final
就像你知道他们把它定下来一样
release of the thing until there's a
释放东西直到有一个
final jar file with the final specs in
具有最终规格的最终jar文件
it right the interfaces of the API right
正确的API接口
and so actually code so that's actually
所以实际上是代码，所以实际上
easy I think that because you don't you
容易，我想是因为你不知道
can't you can't it was equipped you
你能不能装备你
can't publish a jar this has finalized
无法发布已完成的jar
as you see that so that's that's
如您所见，那就是
actually where your assumptions fault
实际上你的假设是错误的
don't work so actually so what's gonna
所以实际上不工作，那该怎么办
happen is there's going to be a
碰巧会有一个
two-phase commit on the project through
通过两阶段提交项目
the spec committee so the project is
规格委员会，所以该项目是
going to do an a standard Eclipse
要做一个标准的Eclipse
development process release review and
开发过程发布审查和
basically say we're done and in that and
基本上说我们已经完成了，并且在那
so the APR file will be versioned and
因此APR文件将被版本控制
final from the open source development
来自开源开发的最终成果
process and the fact that this works is
过程，这是可行的事实是
a happy accident so so actually so
一次幸福的意外
you're good question let me try
你是个好问题，让我尝试
answering and Wayne to tell me what I
回答，韦恩告诉我我
did what I said wrong so Eclipse
我说错了，所以Eclipse
projects have project leaders right so
项目有项目负责人，所以
there is going to be a specification
会有一个规范
project leader and that person may or
项目负责人，该人可以或
may not work for some company but they
可能不适用于某些公司，但他们
have special responsibilities under the
负有特殊责任
EDP so there is going to be a role for
EDP​​，因此将为
leaders in this context the biggest but
在这种情况下最大的领导者
the big point and the most important
重点和最重要
point is the spec lead concept in the
重点是
JCP is tied to IP flows right and super
JCP与IP流紧密相关且超级
and super powers the project leader in
并为项目负责人提供超能力
Eclipse
日食
is a position of responsibility not a
是负责任的职位，而不是
position of authority
权威位置
okay yeah the end so to be honest we
好的，是的，说实话，我们
kind of did that a little bit on purpose
有点故意
for exactly because of because if we put
正是因为如果我们把
oh there is a specification project
哦，有一个规范项目
leader people go AHA there is a spec
领导者去AHA有一个规范
lead so and and that really the the role
领导某某角色
is in is really really different even if
即使真的
the name sounds vaguely familiar no
这个名字听起来含糊不清
that's not true so if you're going to
那不是真的，所以如果你要
make legal claims of compatibility you
向您提出兼容性的法律声明
will have to run a particular binary
将必须运行特定的二进制文件
version of the TCK that is going to
要使用的TCK版本
output a timestamp or something that
输出时间戳或其他内容
says it's this one and that's going to
说是这个，这将
be visible in your public when you
在您公开露面时
publicly disclose your TCK test results
公开披露您的TCK测试结果
so now you can run the open source
所以现在您可以运行开源
version of the TCK and say things like I
版本的TCK并说出类似我的话
ran this version of the TCK and I passed
运行了这个版本的TCK，我通过了
all of the tests
所有测试
that's a truthful statement and you can
那是一个真实的陈述，你可以
always make truthful statements but if
总是如实陈述，但如果
you want to claim compatibility with the
您想声明与
final version of the spec you have to
规范的最终版本
run the special binary version of the
运行特殊的二进制版本
TCK and only that one and make it
TCK，只有那一个，并做到这一点
publicly the result publicly available
公开结果公开
yes
是
yeah there's like a sha-1 or like what
是的，就像sha-1一样
like whatever like implementation detail
就像实现细节一样
no weed so we decided specifically that
没有杂草，所以我们专门决定
we don't want the Eclipse Foundation to
我们不希望Eclipse Foundation
be sort of the central clearinghouse as
作为中央票据交换所
so it is very it's a consciously
所以这是一个有意识的
designed self certification process Mike
设计了自我认证流程Mike
I think we're out of time yeah we should
我认为我们没时间了，是的，我们应该
take this offline anybody who wants to
让这个离线的人想要
leave can leave we can keep
离开可以离开，我们可以保持